[roars]
[narrator] Strange beasts
and monsters.
Vast riches.
Hidden treasures.
Evil haunts.
Uncharted frontiers.
The mysterious unknown.
The people who are captivated
by the magic in those words...
are called...
Hunters!
[theme song plays]
[gasps]
It's so delightful. I love that look.
[Gon] But I've got to say, it was actually
pretty exciting back there.
Huh?
[Gon] I was so scared that all I wanted
to do was run away,
but I couldn't.
'Cause I was excited at the same time!
Isn't that weird?
A x SURPRISING x CHALLENGE
[all panting]
Looks like we made it in time.
But where's Leorio?
There he is.
Man, that stings!
How the hell did I get beat up so badly?
[both gasp]
[Leorio] My memory's so hazy,
I can't remember.
We probably shouldn't tell him
what happened.
You're right.
[Killua] Gon.
[Gon] Killua!
I was starting to think
you weren't gonna make it here.
Or that you didn't make it at all.
I just followed the trail
of Leorio's cologne.
You tracked his scent? That's how?
Man, Gon!
You really are weird, aren't you?
[Satotz] Excellent work, everyone!
The Second Phase will take place here,
in the Visca Forest Park.
So, I shall now take my leave.
I wish you all the very best of luck.
[gates rumbling]
[Menchi] Will all the applicants
who passed the First Phase please enter?
Welcome, all!
I'm Menchi, your examiner
for the Second Phase.
And likewise, I'm Buhara.
[Buhara's stomach rumbles]
-[crowd whispering]
-[man] What was that noise?
Sounds to me like you're getting hungry.
Not just hungry, I'm famished!
Well, there you have it.
The Second Phase...
will be cooking!
-Wait... we're cooking?
-Huh?
What do you mean, we're cooking?
We came here to take the Hunter Exam.
[Menchi] That's right.
The Second Phase of the exam
will be preparing a meal
that'll satisfy our palates.
[man] Why do we have to cook?
Don't you know? It's simple really,
because we're Gourmet Hunters!
Huh? [laughs]
-[crowd laughing]
-[Todo] Talk about a let down!
You hear that? They're Gourmet Hunters!
[laughing continues]
[Menchi sighs]
[Satotz]
Gourmet Hunters, Menchi and Buhara.
Their selection as examiners
could prove quite problematic.
Only 50 applicants left.
But, depending on the task,
it's possible that fewer than ten
will pass the Second Phase.
[laughing continues]
So, you're both Gourmet Hunters.
And what exactly do you want us to make?
Buhara?
Today's required ingredient will be pork.
[man] Pork? You mean like pig meat?
[Buhara] Feel free to use meat from any
species of pig in Visca Forest.
As you see, you'll use these cooking
facilities to prep your pork dishes.
To pass the exam, you must create a dish
to satisfy our discriminating palates.
But we won't be evaluating taste alone.
So take this seriously. Is that clear?
When we've both eaten our fill,
this portion of the exam will be over.
Okay, enough talk.
Let's just get to it, alright?
Let the exam's Second Phase...
[gong sounds]
...begin!
[hurried footsteps]
[Menchi] Any species of pig, huh?
You've got a real mean streak, don't you?
[Buhara] Well, you did say
I got to pick the ingredient.
There's only one species of pig
in Visca Forest,
but you already knew that.
Hmm. I hope nobody gets killed!
[indistinct chatter]
Hey! Piggy!
[Leorio] We gotta catch a pig
and cook it, huh?
Man, this is way easier than
the First Phase
I just hope it's that simple.
[Killua whooping]
[screams]
[all grunt]
What the hell do you think you're doing?
-[Gon] I found them.
-Huh?
[Leorio] Pigs!
They're all... chewing on bones.
Don't tell me... they're carnivores?
[pig roars]
[all screaming]
[man] What the hell's that?
[Leorio panting]
[all screaming]
These pigs are insane!
[Buhara] The Great Stamp!
The most ferocious pig in the whole world.
They use their large, sturdy snouts
to send their predators flying.
You've got to move really quick
unless you want to end up the main course
for their dinner.
[roars]
What?
[gasps]
[yells]
[pig squealing]
Wait a second...
[Gon yells]
[squeals]
Huh, that's it! Their foreheads
are their weak spots.
I see. that makes sense.
They developed tough snouts
to protect their delicate foreheads.
Huh? Oh!
-[chuckles]
-Look at that! They sure caught a lot.
[Satotz] Hmm. This is an exceptional batch
of applicants, indeed.
But the hard part is yet to come.
[Todo] Now, eat the pig
and send me to the next phase.
Okay, time to judge.
Taste testing...
-[Buhara chuckles]
-[bell rings]
-[buzzer sounds]
-Huh?
The pork's overcooked.
It's way too tough.
It totally ruins the flavor.
-Come on! You haven't even tried it!
-I don't have to! It's obvious.
[grunts angrily]
There, I hope you enjoy it.
[bell rings]
[buzzer sounds]
[gasps] But why?
Charred and dry on the outside,
raw on the inside.
Your fire was way too hot.
[bell rings]
[buzzer sounds]
[Menchi] Honestly! They're all just
roasting the entire pig,
like it's the only thing
they know how to do.
None of them have made any effort at all!
[Leorio] Not one applicant has passed yet.
And Menchi has yet to take
a single bite of anyone's entry.
Seriously? Can't anyone out there make
something that'll satisfy my taste buds.
That's it!
The Second Phase is a cooking test,
but they're judging us
based on originality and observation.
Oh, I see.
[Buhara laughs gleefully]
Tell me how much you love it.
Is this supposed to be a kid's meal?
Okay, mine is next.
It's just like the last one!
The next entry's mine, ready to be judged.
Well, finally, something that resembles
an actual dish.
[Kurapika] The challenge is to utilize
the facilities and ingredients provided
to highlight the main feature: the pork.
In short, the taste is insignificant.
[Menchi] Gross!
[gasps]
Presentation is important,
but not at the expense of the flavor.
You're basically no better
than Number 403.
-[buzzer sounds]
-[sneers] Better luck next time.
No better than 403, huh?
[chuckles] That was so much food.
I couldn't take another bite.
Yeah, I'm pretty stuffed, myself.
So, none of you passed to the next phase.
Exam's over!
[crowd gasps]
[Satotz] Just as I feared,
she's reverted to her bad habits.
[Beans] What should we do now, Chairman?
[Chairman] I suppose I have no choice.
It's time for a little outing.
HUNTER GLOSSARY
MENCHI
-[man 1] Nobody passed?
-[man 2] Seriously?
[man 3] Does she really mean that?
[man 4] Wait, so the exam's over?
[man 5] You gotta be kidding!
This is unacceptable.
Do ya hear me? I will not accept this!
[Menchi] Say what you want,
but you still failed.
[Todo] Shut the hell up!
You asked for pork and we gave it to you.
We risked our lives--
Your challenge was to prepare a pork dish
that both examiners would find delicious,
and none of you even came close
to succeeding.
You all did pretty much
the exact same thing.
I mean, it's like you didn't even try
to figure it out.
And when it looked like you had tried,
it was just fancy plating
with no flavor to back it up
It's clear that none of you
took this seriously.
Yeah, but come on, pork? No matter how
you cook it, it's still just pork.
You wanna say that one more time?
If I hear any more crap from you,
I'll shove my arm up your ass,
and knock your teeth out! Got it?
[Buhara] Menchi’s temper is getting
the best of her again.
but I guess it's no surprise.
-There're only a few chefs in the world...
-...you wouldn't know gourmet cuisine...
-...who are good enough to satisfy her.
-You sorry excuse for a human.
I dare you to say it one more time!
So, as I was saying,
not a single one of you has the guts
to cook anything remotely new
or innovative.
Hey! Shut up!
I'm not here because I'm trying
to be some gourmet cook,
but a Hunter!
[crowd] That's right. You tell her!
[Todo]
My goal is to become a Blacklist Hunter,
and no stupid Gourmet Hunter
is gonna tell me I can't.
Then it's too bad that a stupid
Gourmet Hunter is your examiner.
Well, better luck next year, I guess.
Huh? Why, you... Don't mess with me!
[Menchi] Buhara, please don't interfere.
I'm sorry, but it kinda looked like you
were gonna kill him if I didn't step in.
[chuckling] Probably.
Let's get this straight.
We frequently venture into the dens
of ferocious beats,
in search of the finest ingredients.
And every Hunter is proficient
in at least some form of martial art.
You lack focus, and the will
to experiment with new things.
And that alone disqualifies you all
from becoming Hunters.
[Chairman] Well, that said,
it seems a bit excessive
to fail every single applicant.
[man]
The symbol of the Hunter's Association!
It must be someone
from the exam committee.
[crowd grunting]
[coughing and spluttering]
[man] Hey, wait. Who's the old man?
He is the Head of the Exam Committee,
and he's responsible for the Hunter Exam.
Chairman Netero.
Oh, I just work behind the scenes.
It's not all that impressive.
I only intervene in the exams
when little issues like this one pop up.
-Now, dear Menchi.
-Sir.
It's come to my attention that you've
chosen to fail all this year's applicants,
the reason being, as I understand it,
their general reluctance
-to challenge the unknown.
-[Menchi] No.
I'm sorry, sir, but I snapped
when a candidate insulted Gourmet Hunters.
And I'm afraid I made the exam
harder than necessary.
I see, but it seems you're aware
that this exam
was completely unacceptable.
Yes. It's just that I get so emotional
when food is involved.
I'm not suited for this position.
So, I must resign as examiner.
Please let them retake the Second Phase.
Sadly, I can't imagine where we'd begin
to find an examiner on such short notice.
My deepest apologies, sir.
Hold on, I have an idea.
You continue serving as examiner,
but you yourself must participate
alongside this year's applicants,
in completing
whatever challenge you chose.
[gasps]
[Chairman]
Well, what do you say? Sound reasonable?
Surely that would make the applicants
more comfortable with the results.
I suppose you're right.
And I have just the thing
for the new challenge.
We'll all be making boiled eggs!
-[man] Boiled eggs?
-[indistinct chatter]
[Menchi] Chairman, since I see
you brought your airship,
would you mind taking us all
to Split Mountain?
[Chairman] Split Mountain?
Oh, I see. Yes, of course!
This is it.
Take a look at what's down there.
[man] What is that?
-A spider-eagle's web.
-They built their webs way down there?
[earth rumbling]
[gasps]
Look past the web to what's underneath.
-[Killua] Hey, those are--
-[Menchi] Those are the spider-eagle eggs.
[Chairman] Spider-eagles build their webs
in deep ravines like this one.
It helps protect their eggs
from predators.
That's what makes these eggs one of
the most difficult ingredients to obtain.
Also, the eggs are commonly known
as "Dream Eggs."
-Hey, wait a minute. Do you mean--
-[Menchi] You bet I do.
Huh?
[all gasping]
[exhales]
Even if she grabs a few eggs,
how's she gonna climb back up?
[all gasp]
[Leorio] Hey! She jumped down!
Is she trying to get herself killed?
No, she's not.
[gasping]
That looks so fun.
This ravine has updrafts
that are crucial to the spider-eagle.
Once they hatch, the wind currents
help guide their newborn chicks
as they fly up to safety.
There! Now I just need to boil it
and I'll be set!
You gotta be kidding!
You mean, you really expect us
to jump down there? That's crazy!
[Gon] I've been waiting
for something like this! [laughs]
[whooping]
Alright, I'm in.
Wait, I still haven't finished
explaining everything.
[man laughs] Later!
-What are we waiting for?
-Hold on! Don't let go yet.
-Why? What's wrong?
-No wind.
-The updrafts don't happen all the time.
-Huh?
[man screaming]
When do you think
the next one comes along?
Any minute now.
Oh, crap! What the...?
It appears the web isn't strong enough
to support all this weight.
Gon, can we go yet?
Damn! I can't wait any longer.
[men screaming]
It's about to snap!
Okay, now!
[chuckles]
What about you guys?
I'm guessing you quit?
[Chairman] Conceding takes courage, too.
Unbelievable! This is way better
than what they sell in the store.
[munching]
I can see why
they're called Dream Eggs.
[Gon] Hey! Mr. Todo!
The egg's really good.
Do you wanna try it?
It's delicious.
[Menchi] The joy of discovering
something delicious.
And now, you know what it feels like.
That feeling is
what we risk our lives for.
I lost fair and square.
Next year, I'll be back.
[narrator] The applicants have learned
a valuable lesson.
Whether Blacklist or Gourmet,
no one comes by
the title of Hunter easily.
It requires a staggering amount
of determination.
Only 42 candidates remain.
[theme music plays]
[Gon] Next time,
"Showdown on the Airship."
Hey! Use soap when you wash your hands!
Right!